ILGWU Political Department Records 5780/103
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Political Department Records
1960-1984
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780/103
42.5 cubic feet
42.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection contains correspondence, memoranda, and reports relating to the Political Department's lobbying activities in Washington, D. C. Also contained in this collection are letters and receipts documenting campaign contributions, alphabetical files on states, as well as files on local unions, joint boards, and regional departments. The records of the Political Department also contain ephemeral printed material relating to political campaigns, including pamphlets, posters, and fliers.
5516143
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
C. Berne, May 20, 2009
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 20, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
The Political Department of the ILGWU was founded in 1947, under the direction of Gus Tyler. Its primary function was to engage union members and their families in political issues at the local, state, and national levels. This engagement was achieved through conferences, publications, and other communications. Educational work was a hallmark of the department, as were the department's legislative monitoring, research activities, and organizing for electoral campaigns.
David Wells joined the Political Department in 1952, eventually becoming Assistant Director. In 1956, Evelyn Dubrow was named the ILGWU's chief lobbyist in Washington, D.C., and became a well-known fixture on Capitol Hill.
Scope and Contents
The Political Department records are constituted of two accessions of Evelyn Dubrow papers and one accession of records from the department. Included are correspondence and memoranda, reports of lobbying activities, subject files on states and ILGWU affiliates, receipts for campaign contributions, ephemera from political campaigns.
These records are complemented by one accession of the Gus Tyler papers (5780/088) that includes records relating to his work as founding director of the Political Department, in addition to some of his other activities relating to the union. An oral history interview with David Wells (6036/076), in which the former Assistant Director discusses his work with the Union and in New York City, also complements the records of the Political Department.
Taken together, these materials, the Political Department records, Evelyn Dubrow papers, Gus Tyler papers, and the David Wells interview, document a considerable range of the Political Department's work from its founding in 1948 to its merger with ACTWU in 1995.
The Politcal Departmen records contain correspondence, memoranda, and reports relating to the Political Department's lobbying activities in Washington, D.C. Also included in this collection are letters and receipts documenting campaign contributions, alphabetical files on states, as well as files on local unions, joint boards, and regional departments. The records of the Political Department also contain ephemeral printed material relating to political campaigns, including pamphlets, posters, and fliers.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/119: ILGWU Political Department, Evelyn Dubrow Papers 5780/142: ILGWU Political/Legislative Department, Evelyn Dubrow Papers 5780/088: ILGWU Gus Tyler Papers 6036/080: Evelyn Dubrow papers 6036/080 P: Evelyn Dubrow Photographs 6036/076 OH: Daniel Soyer ILGWU Heritage Project
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--United States.; Industrial relations--United States.; Dubrow, Evelyn; Wells, David; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Political Dept.
5516143
- 50th Anniversary - Union Health Center, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Mobile Voter Registration Units, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- E. Howard Molisani, Election Campaign, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photographs (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Podell Campaign, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Newspapers (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Proportional Representation, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Radio Stations - New York State (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Leonard Sand, 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Social Security, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Social Security Improvement, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Training Institute Statistics, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Training Institute Schedule, 1961-1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Memos to Gus Tyler, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Materials from Gus Tyler, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Wagner Mayoralty - Primary Campaign, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- David I. Wells - Expenses, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- David I. Wells - Expenses, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- David I. Wells - Expenses, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- David I. Wells - Expenses, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- David I. Wells - Expenses, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- David I. Wells - Expenses, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Goldberg Gubernatorial Campaign, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Election, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Humphrey Election, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Murray Baron for US Senate, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Legislative Representation in New York State, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- AFL-CIO News Subscriptions, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Civil Rights Petitions and Posters, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Mayoralty Campaign - Lindsay, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- G.E. (General Electric) Strike Fund, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Lentol-Mintz Unemployment Insurance Petitions, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Liberal Party, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- The New Republic, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Diagrams (Box 2, Folder 11)
- David Wells, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- David I. Wells - Expenses, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- David I. Wells - Expenses, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Ben Davidson, Liberal Party, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- O. General, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- G.E.B. Reports, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- I.L.G. Intro - Office, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Political Dept. Invoices, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Letter Forms, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Out-of-Town Memo D.D., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Boston Joint Board Kramer, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Central States Region, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Cloak Out-of-Town Department (Rubin), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Eastern Region Department, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Midwest (Bialis), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- New York City Locals, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Northeast Department (Gingold), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Ohio-Kentucky Region (Kirtzman), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Pacific Coast Region (Otto), 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Southeast Region (Kehrer), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- South Jersey and Philadelphia, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Upper South Department, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- January, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- February, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- March, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- April, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- May, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- June, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- July, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- August, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- September, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- October, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- November, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- December, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- American Veteran Committee, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Cope Political Memos, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- AFL-CIO Cope General, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Order for Cope Calendars, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- AFL-CIO IUD Reports, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- AFL-CIO IUD General, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- General "A", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Liberal Party, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- New York State Registration Dates, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Counties, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- "B" General, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Bills and Amendments, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Cope General, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Cope Monthly Memos, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Cope Political Memos, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Cope Conference, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- AFL-CIO General, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Brazilian Team, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- "C" General, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Carswell Nomination, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Citizens' Research Foundation, 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Citizens Union, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Civil Liberties Union, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Committee on Human Rights, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Congress, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- CFA, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Civil Rights, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Consumers Legislation, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Orders for Consumer Foundation of America Leaflets, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- HR 14931 - Consumer Bill Which Includes Class Action Proposal, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Consumer Assembly, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Current Issues, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- "D" General, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Democratic National Committee, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Democratic Party, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Evelyn Dubrow Expenses, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Things From D.W. Files, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Electoral College Reform, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Election, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- "F" General, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Facts About Congress, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- "G" General, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Group Research, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- "H" General, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Health - General, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Housing - General, 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Low and Moderate Income Housing Mortgages by Private Owners, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- "I" General, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- International and National Union Presidents (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Issues, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- "J" General, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Jewish Labor Committee, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- "K" General, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- "L" General, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- League of Women Voters, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Liberal Party, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Lobbying Reports, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Mexican Border, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- "M" General, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Maida Springer Assignment, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Minimum Wage, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Miscellaneous Articles, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Mountain Artisans Inc., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- "N" General [Folder 1 of 2], 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- "N" General [Folder 2 of 2], 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- National Consumer League, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- National Health Insurance, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- National Municipal League, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- National Sharecroppers, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- New York City, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- "O" General, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- OEO Mimeo, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Political Statistics, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- "R" General, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Registration, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Right-to-Work, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- "S" General, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Senate General, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- "T" General, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Taxes, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Teacher Corps, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Trade Bill [Folder 1 of 3], 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Trade Bill [Folder 2 of 3], 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Trade Bill [Folder 3 of 3], 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Textile Apparel Import [Folder 1 of 4], 1970 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Textile Apparel Import [Folder 2 of 4], 1970 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Textile Apparel Import [Folder 3 of 4], 1970 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Textile Apparel Import [Folder 4 of 4], 1970 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- "U" General, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- "V" General (Box 6, Folder 28)
- "W" General, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- GEB Report, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- ILGWU Benefit Funds, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Political Department Invoices, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Form Letters, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- ILG Intra-Office [Folder 1 of 2], 1971 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- ILG Intra-Office [Folder 2 of 2], 1971 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Boston Joint Board, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Central States Region, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Cloak Out-of-Town Department, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Eastern Region Department, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Midwest Department, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- New York City Locals, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Northeast Department, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Ohio-Kentucky Region, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Pacific Coast Region, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Puerto Rico, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Southeast Region Department, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- South Jersey-Philadelphia Joint Board, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Upper South Department, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- December, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- November, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- October, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- September, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- August, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- July, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- June, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- "A" General, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- AFL-CIO Cope Memos, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Order Forms (Box 7, Folder 23)
- May, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- April, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- March, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- February, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- January, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Monthly Cope Memos, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Order Forms, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- AFL-CIO News, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- AFL-CIO Cope General [Folder 1 of 2], 1971 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- AFL-CIO Cope General [Folder 2 of 2], 1971 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- "B" General, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- AFL-CIO Statements [Folder 1 of 3], 1971 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- AFL-CIO Statements [Folder 2 of 3], 1971 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- AFL-CIO Statements [Folder 3 of 3], 1971 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Bills and Amendments [Folder 1 of 2], 1971 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Bills and Amendments [Folder 2 of 2], 1971 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- "C" General, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- CFA, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Child Development Act, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Citizen Union, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Consumer Newsweek, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Replies From Congressmen on HR 2007, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Congress, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Consumer Assembly, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Consumer Legislation - General, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- "D" General, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Day Care Center [Folder 1 of 2], 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Day Care Center [Folder 2 of 2], 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Democratic National Committee, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Democratic Party, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- "E" General, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Education - General, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Evelyn Dubrow Expenses, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Election Statistics, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- "F" General, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- "Fact" D.N.C., 1971 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- AFL-CIO - General, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- "G" General, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Group Research, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Gus Staff Mailing, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- "H" General, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Health - General, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Human Rights and Genocide Treaties, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- AFL-CIO IUD General [Folder 1 of 3], 1971 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- AFL-CIO IUD General [Folder 2 of 3], 1971 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- AFL-CIO IUD General [Folder 3 of 3], 1971 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- "I" General, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Issues, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- "J" General, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Jewish Labor Committee, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- "L" General, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- League of Women Voters, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Legislative Newsletters, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Legislative Reappointment, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Lobbying Reports, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- "M" General, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Mexican Border, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Minimum Wage [Folder 1 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Minimum Wage [Folder 2 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Minimum Wage [Folder 3 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- "N" General, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- National Consumer League, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- National Health Insurance, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- National Sharecroppers, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- New Jersey - General, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- New York State, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Newsletters, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- New York City, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- "O" General, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Office of Economic Opportunity, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Occupational Health and Safety, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- "P" General, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Pension and Welfare Bill (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Photographs (Box 9, Folder 18)
- "R" General, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Replies From Senators on S. 2007, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Registration (Box 9, Folder 21)
- "S" General, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Senate - General, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Social Security - General, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- "T" General, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Textile Apparel Import, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- "U" General, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- "W" General, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- White House Conference on Aging, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- ILGWU Political Department, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Political Department Invoices, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- G.E.B. Report (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Form Letters, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- ILG Inter-Office, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- ILG Inter-Office, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Boston Joint Board, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Central States Region, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Joint Council of the Cloak Out-of-Town Department, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Eastern Region Department (Kramer), 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Midwest (Bialis), 1972 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- New York City Locals, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Northeast Department, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Ohio-Kentucky Region (Kirtzman), 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Pacific Coast Region (Otto), 1972 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Southeast Region (Kehrer), 1972 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- South Jersey-Philadelphia Joint Board (Dobren), 1972 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Puerto Rico, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Upper South Department, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- January, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- February, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- March, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- April, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- May, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- June, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- July, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- August, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- September, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- October, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- November, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- December, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- "A" General, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Cope Calendars, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Orders for Cope Calendars, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Cope Conferences, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Cope Political Memos, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- AFL-CIO Statements, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Orders for Nixonomics, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- AFL-CIO General, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- AFL-CIO General, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- AFL-CIO Cope General, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- AFL-CIO IUD General (Box 12, Folder 1)
- AFL-CIO News Memos, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Asbestos Hazard Material, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- "B" General, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Bills and Amendments, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Burke-Hartke, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- "C" General, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Consumer Federation of America, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Consumer Federation of America, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Child Development Act, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Citizens' Committee for Children, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Citizens' Research Foundation (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Citizens Union, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Civil Rights, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Congress, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Congressional Action, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Congressional Candidates, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Consumer Articles, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Consumer Assembly, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Consumer Legislation and General, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Consumer Newsweek, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Day Care, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 22)
- "D" General, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 23)
- Democratic Party, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 24)
- Evelyn Dubrow Expense Account, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 25)
- "E" General, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 26)
- Education, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 27)
- Education General (School Construction), 1972 (Box 12, Folder 28)
- Election, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 29)
- "F" General, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 30)
- Emergency Disputes, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 31)
- Presidential Elections, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 32)
- "Fact" DNC (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Economy - Phase I and Phase II, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Elections, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Federal Registers, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Federationist, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- "G" General, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Group Research, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Gus - Staff Mailings, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- "H" General, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Order Forms, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Human Rights and Genocide Treaties, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- "I" General, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Inflation, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- ILGWU Convention Resolutions, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- ILGWU Convention - Miami, Florida, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Issues (Box 13, Folder 16)
  Scope and Contents
  In Spanish and English
- "J" General, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Jewish Labor Committee, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- "K" General, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- James E. Keene, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 20)
- "L" General, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 21)
- Labor - General, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 22)
- League of Women Voters, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 23)
- Legislative Newsletter, 1969-1972 (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Legislative Newsletter, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 25)
- Legislative Newsletter Lists, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 26)
- Lobbying Report (Evelyn Dubrow), 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 27)
- Legislative News (Letter Lists), 1965-1972 (Box 13, Folder 28)
- "M" General, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 29)
- Minimum Wage Bill, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 30)